Email: Web: spikegrobstein@mac.com www.lamestuff.com

# **Objective:**

Being self-motivated and having experience and extreme interest in art and technology, I hope to work someplace where I can use my programming skills to complete my work as fast and high quality as possible while continuing my education in the related fields.

### **Education:**

Linden High School- 1999 graduate. Rutgers University- New Brunswick, NJ (1999-2000)

### **Computer Skills:**

Knowledge of computer and computer network architecture and security. Understanding of secure application design concepts.

Experience use and administration of MacOS X, Linux (Gentoo/Ubuntu), NetBSD, BeOS, Windows, Solaris. Photoshop, ImageReady, Illustrator, GoLive, AfterEffects, Premier, Quark XPress, Freehand, InDesign, Microsoft Office (some Excel scripting), BBEdit, XCode, Quickbooks, FilemakerPro, HTML, CSS, LDAP, MySQL, CVS, Firewalls (iptables).

Programming in REALbasic, Java, C, Objective-C (Cocoa), PERL, BASH, Applescript, VBA, PHP, Ruby / Ruby on Rails, Python.

### **Experience:**

National Flag & Display - New York, NY (PT August 2003 - Present)

Flags, Banners, Stage Backdrops, etc.

Production Artist / IT Department

Prepared artwork for output on digital injet machines (on vinyl and fabric), screenprinting, appliqué and embroidery. Redraw designs and logos. Operated plotter for appliqué and screenprinting jobs. Computer tech support for the PC and Mac network (Windows 2003 Fileserver, OSX and OS9 Macs, Windows 98/2000/XP) at all 3 company locations. Wrote scripts for repetative tasks in the art department (file labeling, jpeg proofs, emailing and CD burning for outsourced jobs) using Applescript and PERL. Assembled hardware and configured software for FTP server running Gentoo Linux including automatic email notification of file submissions. Wrote web application for client file submissions. Created and designed corporate website using PHP, PERL,CSS and XHTML with seamless integration with FTP server's web frontend. Also miscellaneous application and script development and documentation.

Ivy League Graphics, LLC - Plainfield, NJ (PT January 2005 - December 2005)

Garment Screenprinting / Embroidery

Co-owner / Art Director / IT Manager / Sales

Involvement in setting up the new business including creating relationships with vendors, purchasing computer and production hardware and software. Billing, collections, tax information and sales. Established relationships with vendors and clients.

**Vericon, LLC** - Bourbon, IN (PT August 2004 - February 2005)

ISP Turnkey Solutions / ISP Branding

Lead Graphic Artist

Designed batches of related graphics for branded websites and software following predetermined size requirements. Worked from home and emailed art making revisions as necessary. Designs included web and print graphics.

Email: Web: spikegrobstein@mac.com www.lamestuff.com

# **Experience (cont.):**

Angry Lamb - New York, NY (On Call December 2003 - October 2004)

On-Site Computer Technician

Traveled to client offices to configure and/or analyze and repair computer problems, both hardware and software. Had to work in environments with mixed platforms (OSX, Windows 98/2000/XP and Windows 2003 Server). Wrote Applescripts to automate connecting to shared network drives. Put together Microsoft Word documentation for employees to access shared network drives.

Viscotec USA, LLC.- Kenilworth, NJ (August 2002 - July 2003)

Direct ink jet printing on fabrics

**Production Artist** 

Set up artwork for the RIP, contacted customers about questions and problems, wrote software to automate DVD-RAM backup system for OSX using Obj-C and PERL, operated Solaris based RIP over Telnet, and operated printing machines. Also created their new web site using hand-coded HTML and a PERL template engine which I wrote.

**Jersey Graphics, Inc.**- Plainfield, NJ (August 2000 - August 2002, PT August 2003 - Present) Currently known as A. Haupt / Jersey Graphics One, LLC - Maspeth, NY

Course and Course and visiting / Englandiday.

Garment Screenprinting/ Embroidery

Art Director

Scanning, artwork re-creation from customer hardcopy and original artwork, color separations for screenprinting, invoicing, customer service, screenprinting and training of other employees, contacted customers regarding questions about artwork and other aspects of orders.

### **DGM Computer Graphics**- Roselle, NJ (summers of 1996-1998)

**Digital Prepress** 

Artist/ Scanning Technician

Artwork re-creation, photo retouching and manipulation, color correction, flatbed and drum scanning of reflective art and transparencies.

# **Accomplishments:**

Currently run a webserver (Gentoo Linux/ PPC) with SSH, FTP, Apache, MySQL, PHP and Ruby on Rails with over 20 users and websites. Set up personal file server (Gentoo Linux/PPC) on home LAN for network access storage and automated daily snapshot backups of webserver.

Created a full-functioning invoicing system tailored for freelance jobs and scripts for emailing PDFs of invoices and quotes in Filemaker Pro.

Wrote a program for manipulating Nintendo Gamecube disc images (.gcm and .iso) for Linux and OSX that runs on both PPC and x86 chips in ANSI C. Wrote a program for extracting and injecting graphics as well as editing meta-data (titles) for Nintendo (NES) game ROM files. Written in ANSI C for \*nix and OSX and is open source. <a href="http://nesromtool.sourceforge.net">http://nesromtool.sourceforge.net</a> <a href="http://gcmtool.sourceforge.net">http://gcmtool.sourceforge.net</a>>

Created several applications in Java using TCP and UDP socket communication utilizing the Hotline Connect and Hotline Tracker protocols including a Hotline Connect client and Hotline Tracker server and client.

Developed the only working Mac client for the now defunct ScourXChange network using REALbasic.